profitistic.com 2014-06-29

# Monetise | Privacy Policy

Monetise understands the importance of privacy, and we strive to keep sensitive and personal information confidential. We request that all affiliates and merchants/advertisers read this policy in order to better understand how the information you provide to us and that we may otherwise collect may be used. If you have any queries relating to this policy, please do not hesitate to contact us at [info@monetise.co.uk](mailto:info@monetise.co.uk).

**Information**

We collect information based on the following criteria:

  1. You are a registered Monetise merchant,
  2. You are a registered Monetise affiliate, or
  3. You have applied to become a registered merchant or affiliate.

If you are one of these three users, when you register and start using our site located at [www.monetise.co.uk](http://www.monetise.co.uk/) (the “Site”), we require relevant program information, including but not limited to log-in, contact, company, website, website user and payment data in order to manage your account and provide you with the services requested. In addition once you are a member of Monetise, we require sales and earnings data, and we collect performance statistics related to your Monetise affiliate program(s) in order to properly compensate our users.  
Information is collected by Monetise but is the sole property of the advertiser and is shared only with the advertiser.

**Contacting us with a question:**  When you contact us with a question or suggestion, we may collect your name, e-mail address and any comments you have. We only use this information to respond to and/or resolve your question or concern.

**Information collected by Cookies.**  We do not collect data while you browse our public pages of the Site although Monetise uses cookies to track leads and sales for the purpose of properly compensating affiliates. When a web visitor views an affiliate page and clicks on a merchant link, a cookie is placed on the visitor’s hard drive. If the visitor performs a prescribed action (for example, signing up for a newsletter) or buys something, the cookie records their action. If the visitor revisits the merchant’s site and buys anything else, the cookie will also track subsequent sales and credit the appropriate affiliate (depending on the cookie’s specified duration). We are collecting this information in order to track customers or sales.  
Monetise does not intentionally use cookies to track personal information. However, systems of some partner merchants may use portions of personal information (in the form of a customer or order ID) to track customers or sales. A merchant may choose to pass Monetise the ID, but without any other identifying/related information.  
Monetise does nothing to prevent the disabling or blocking of cookies. If a visitor chooses to disable or block cookies, any leads or sales the visitor makes will not be able to be tracked.

**When We Disclose Information**  
We share specific information only with registered Monetise merchants and affiliates in order for them to make educated decisions while forming affiliations. Merchants and affiliates who are considering forming an affiliation may view pertinent company, contact and performance information, and they may contact each other to solicit affiliation or find out additional details. After an affiliation has been formed, we share sales and performance information necessary to calculate commission payments from merchants to affiliates. In addition, merchants may email or contact existing affiliates with potential offers and news.

Occasionally we may share category information or general user statistics with potential partners. No personal identifying information will be included in such information and your identity will remain absolutely anonymous.

**How We Protect Your Information**  
We employ a number of safeguards to protect your information. Every user creates a unique password that only the user knows. You should never share your password and take usual recommended precautions (use a combination of numbers, letters and upper- and lowercase; change your password periodically). Particularly sensitive information, such as commission and earnings information are only available to the directly associated merchant and affiliate(s), and some information can only be accessed by system administrators. Our servers are backed up daily and our web hosting features triple redundancy.

**Sharing and Selling Data**

Monetise does not share or sell your data to unaffiliated third parties. It does share data with member merchants and affiliates, as outlined in “When We Disclose Information,” in order for merchants and affiliates to make informed decisions about the affiliations they make.

In addition, from time to time, we may share non-user specific, aggregate information, or company names for the purpose of educating potential merchants and affiliates. No personal identifying information will be included in such information and your identity will remain absolutely anonymous.

Finally, in case required by law, we may disclose personal information.

**Access, Update and Deletion**  
We want your information and preferences to be accurate and complete. If you would like to access or update the personal information we maintain about you in our systems, please contact us at info@monetise.co.uk. You may use the same contact information above to send us a request that we delete personally identifiable information stored in the databases we actively use. Unless restricted by law, we will take all reasonable steps to functionally delete such information from our database(s), although we may keep a copy for archival purposes for as long as necessary in our opinion. We will respond to your request to access, update or delete your information within thirty (30) business days.

**Surveys**  
Occasionally, Monetise may conduct voluntary surveys for its own business development purposes. The results of these surveys may be shared or disclosed, but company- or website-specific data will not be released without first securing necessary written consent.

**Minors**

We do not knowingly solicit information from users under the age of 18 and require all affiliates to certify that they are legal adults, 18 years or older.

**General Notes About Our Privacy Policy**  
Monetise websites contain links to other sites. We are not responsible for their privacy policies and urge you to review their respective policies.

We are also not responsible for the privacy policies of our partner merchants’ and affiliates’ sites and advise you to familiarize yourself with their respective policies.

**Change in Our Privacy Policy**  
If there are changes or additions to this Privacy Policy, we will post those changes here so that you will always know what information we collect online or offline, how we use it and what choices you have. Regardless of any changes we make to our Privacy Policy, we will only use your personal information in accordance with the version of the Privacy Policy in place at the time you provided your information unless you give us your consent to do otherwise.
